Okay, so do you
remember my story from
the start of this
phase where I told
you how I quit
a bigger channel to
focus on a new
one and then enabled
my income to crease
but my workload went
down? That just doesn't
make any sense, right?
How can less views
and less time and
energy make you more?
Well, the reason this
happened is because of
something called positioning. This
is the secret to
success and most people
don't even know it
exists. So in the
next few videos, I'm
going to teach you
what positioning is, the
positioning mistakes to avoid
that are going to
stop your pipeline from
working, and then I'm
going to show you
how to position yourself
using my positioning system,
and I'm going to
introduce you to an
AI bot that I
built especially for this
task, which you are
going to flipping love.
And at the end,
we're then going to
audit your channel and
your email and your
offer to help work
out where you might
need to focus on
your positioning so that
you can turn views
into sales and grow
a following much easier
over the long term.
Now, to start, I've
got to convince you
of just how important
and powerful positioning is.
So let me show
you a few people
who have nailed this.
This is Shrey. He
went from 400 to
358 ,000 subscribers in
just over a year
and made $15 ,000
in a week launching
his first low ticket
product. This is BGO.
He went from a
few hundred subs to
10K in 90 days,
and within a year,
he launched both a
high ticket product and
a mastermind. This is
Meadow, who I spoke
about earlier. Meadow hit
40 ,000 subscribers in
a year, even though
her first five videos
flopped because she kept
following the system. Dado
12Xed his investment in
six months with just
one of his offers.
He launched in that
time, making 50K in
10 days. The two
Toms you can see
here both did 25K
in 30 days. Jacob,
20K in a month
with his new offer.
Ross hit 44K months
despite his views going
backwards at first. Dimitri
had 10 weeks of
no sales before he
suddenly hit 30K, then
70K. Tony had a
41K month. I'm going
to stop because I
could do this for
an hour and a
half. But the point
is this. This works.
But also, I need
to remind you that
when you make changes
based on what you'll
discover in the following
videos, it's very likely
that you're going to
get a lot of
money. And that's exactly
what happened to many
of those examples. So
prepare yourself for a
bumpy ride. All right.
So let's start with
a game that's going
to show you the
basics of what positioning
is and why it's
so powerful for building
a channel and business.
And to do that,
I'm going to flash
up an image and
I want you to
say out loud the
first word that comes
to your mind when
you see it. All
right. Image number one.
And then here's image
number two. All right.
Now I'm going to
read your mind. I'm
going to tell you
that when you saw
the Red Bull logo,
you thought energy. And
when you saw Volvo,
you thought safety. It's
creepy, right? But how
can showing a logo
that fast make someone
think a word like
that? And why does
this even matter to
you? Well, let's start
with the reason that
happened by breaking it
down into three simple
steps. So step one
is all about working
out who the perfect
buyer for your offer
is. So for Volvo,
that's parents with young
kids. And for Red
Bull, it's millennials. Step
two. You just need
to work out what
the biggest problem they
know they have is
and want solving. So
for Volvo, the problem
their perfect buyers have
is safety. And for
Red Bull, it's low
energy. And then in
step three, all you
need to do is
you write a very
short line of text
that says, we solve
this problem for this
person. So Volvo would
say, we make cars
that keep families safe.
And Red Bull would
say, we make drinks
that give millennials energy.
Then all you do
is you position. Every
single thing you make
as the solution to
this problem. So if
you look at Volvo,
their TV ads, their
social media, and all
of their marketing for
over 30 years has
said, we keep families
safe. And then their
product is built to
deliver the same result
too. And then Red
Bull does exactly the
same thing and positions
everything they make as
the solution to the
problem their target buyers
have. And their product
gets that results too.
And Volvo and Red
Bull have repeated this
for 30 years. So
what Volvo never does
is make marketing that
looks like this and
position its cars on
how much horsepower they
have, because their product
doesn't do that firstly,
but they're also their
target audience doesn't care
about speed is quite
literally the opposite. If
they did that, it
would put them into
competition with every other
car company in the
world who competes on
speed. So doing this
meant they can differentiate
in a very competitive
landscape and become known
for a word in
an instance. So if
you're like, I want
a car that keeps
the kids safe, you
don't buy a Ferrari.
You just think Volvo.
Red Bull would also
never make marketing claiming
how amazing their drink
tastes, because if they
were honest, they'd say
this, Red Bull tastes
like Volvo fuel. And
then they would have
to compete with 99
% of drinks out
there who all claim
they taste amazing. So
positioning is simply the
art of working out
who your dream buyer
is, what the big
problem they really care
about is, and then
how to position your
video. Emails and your
offer as the solution
to that problem for
that person so that
you can then become
known for just one
thing and a scene
on the expert on
that thing. And if
you look at many
of the most successful
people in this space,
most of them are
known as the something
guy or the something
lady. So that might
be the ads guy
or the cheese lady
or the narcissist lady.
But getting yourself to
this point where people
know you for the
problem you solve is
the most powerful YouTube
hack of all time.
And it's the only
real way. That you
can compete on YouTube
now it's so crowded.
So we use this
to differentiate. The thing
is, how can being
known for just solving
one problem for one
group of people actually
work to grow your
channel and business? Because
it sounds like you
need more people and
more problems to talk
about so you can
become a success. Well,
let me show you
what happens when you
don't take this route
so you can see
just how important it
is. So here's poor
old Austin. He's not
a client. I have
no affiliation with him.
He got nearly 4
million views on this
video, which is absolutely
exceptional. But then his
next video got 9
,000 views and then
this one got 2
,000. How on earth
can someone get 4
million views on a
video and then bring
back such a small
amount of them? Well,
it's because he's not
positioned his channel to
solve a problem for
a specific person. So
if we look at
his viral video, let's
just ask, who is
this for and what
is the problem it
solves? So in the
thumbnail, there's this picture
of a notebook and
it's in a supermarket.
And it says the
90 cent secret. And
then his title is
the pocket notebook is
slowly replacing my phone.
So who's that for?
I have no idea.
It's so broad. Maybe
it's people who want
something cheap. Is it
business people? Let's just
guess, I don't know,
students for now. And
then what's the problem
it solves? Well, based
on this packaging, it's
maybe replacing tech with
cheap analog things. All
right. So now let's
look at his video.
Got 9 ,000 views
called Use this to
finally destroy procrastination. So
can you see the
problem?
Suddenly, well, who's the
person? Same, maybe it's
business people. And then
if you think about
the problem too, well,
procrastination is very different
to replacing analog tech.
So the people who
loved his notebook video
had absolutely no reason
to click on that
as they didn't come
to him for that
problem. And they don't
know him for that
problem. They know him
for one thing, notebooks.
And just to confirm
what I'm showing you
here. So let's look
a few videos later.
He then posts a
pocket notebook, transformed my
mental clarity. Now I've
got 167. I'm going
to show you the
video. It's going to
get you 7 ,000
views because it's the
same person and the
same problem. And it
matched what people came
to him for. So
even though his viral
video exploded, none of
the videos he makes
on his channel aligns
with it. So he
can't get people to
watch content over and
over again, doesn't build
trust. It doesn't then
build a returning audience.
And if he'd used
my sales system wouldn't
have worked. So what
you have to understand
here is that YouTube
is absolutely brutal.
or you do things
that your viewers look
at and go, that's
not what I come
to this channel for,
then your views crash.
But even worse are
these three things. So
firstly, if only one
in four of your
videos appeal to a
viewer, they'll only watch
this amount of your
content in that 30
day period. We really
want to try and
warm people up so
you won't make any
sales because they won't
get hot enough. Secondly,
if you keep making
videos about different problems
and viewers ignore them,
YouTube's just going to
stop testing your videos
with that group of
people. And then thirdly,
if your email or
lead magnet only appeals
to one in four
of your viewers who
discovered your channel, then
you could be sitting
there thinking, well, I
have an email list
of 3000 people. I'm
ready to launch an
offer. But you don't.
You have an email
list of 750 people
who might be interested
in your offer because
only one in four
of the things you
ever send them is
relevant to the problem
they actually came to
you with. So you
basically have a cold,
small email list that
won't convert and a
channel that's a fourth
of the size you
think. And a way
cold audience when it
comes to buying because
they don't think of
you as the expert
in one thing. They
just think you're some
sort of generalist they
ignore most of the
time. But I know
what you're thinking, Ed.
I don't want to
talk about the same
problem over and over
again and get less
views. But here's the
thing. You don't have
to. Meadow blew up
doing this and so
does Shrey. And they
still can talk about
anything they like. So
what's this video next
where I'm going to
show you how to
work out your positioning
so that you can
talk about hundreds of
different things too.